<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>By the Queene. A proclamation to restraine accesse to the court, of all such as are not bound to ordinarie attendance, or that shall not be otherwise licenced by her Maiestie</title>
            <title>Proclamations. 1592-10-12</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1558-1603 : Elizabeth I)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1592</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 5 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A21893</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 8223</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S115475</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99850694</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99850694</idno>
            <idno type="VID">15918</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A21893)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 15918)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 565:82)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>By the Queene. A proclamation to restraine accesse to the court, of all such as are not bound to ordinarie attendance, or that shall not be otherwise licenced by her Maiestie</title>
                  <title>Proclamations. 1592-10-12</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1558-1603 : Elizabeth I)</author>
                  <author>Elizabeth I, Queen of England, 1533-1603.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>By the deputies of Christopher Barker, printer to the Queenes most excellent Maiestie,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Imprinted at London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1592.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Because of plague.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the Bodleian Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Plague --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>England --  Court and courtiers --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>England --  Proclamations --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2008-08</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-11</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-05</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-05</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="royal_proclamation">
            <pb facs="tcp:15918:1"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 8 -->
            <head>
               <g ref="char:leaf">❧</g> By the Queene.</head>
            <head type="sub">
               <g ref="char:leaf">❧</g> A Proclamation to reſtraine acceſſe to the Court, of all ſuch as are not bound to ordinarie attendance, or that ſhall not be other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe licenced by her Maieſtie.</head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">T</seg>He Queenes Maieſtie vpon good conſideration that her Court may (with Gods fauour) bee the better preſerued from the inſection of ſickeneſſe in this time, commandeth that no maner perſons, but ſuch as haue cauſe to remaine or come to her Court for their ordinarie attendance vpon her Maieſties per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon, or to do ſeruice in her Court, ſhal make their repaire to her Court, or with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in two miles of the ſame, vpon paine to bee committed to priſon for their con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tempt. And where by her Maieſties commandement there are certaine orders made, who, and how many ſhall be commanded to attend for the ſeruice of her Maieſtie, either for her Chamber, or for her Houſhold, or for attendance vpon her Counſailors, or other her Maieſties ordinarie ſeruants in Court, and that no moe ſhall bee allowed to ſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low the Court, or to enter into the ſame: Her Maieſtie ſtraightly chargeth both her Counſailors and her prin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cipall Officers of her Chamber, and of her Houſhold, that they ſee the ſame orders duely obſerued, and that ſuch as ſhall breake the ſame orders, may be ſharply puniſhed. And conſidering the Terme of S. Michael which ſhould haue begun at Weſtminſter the ninth of this moneth, is adiourned, as by her proclamation is notified, her Maieſtie alſo commandeth, That all priuate ſuitors ſhall forbeare to come to the Court, where her Maie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſlie ſhall reſide, vntil the twentieth of Nouember next. And if there ſhall be any extraordinarie cauſe for any per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon to come to the Court with matter to be certified to her Maieſtie, or to any of her priuie Counſaile, who ſhall require to be heard preſently without further delaie, the ſame partie ſhal not enter within the gates of her Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ieſties Court, vntill hee haue either by her Maieſties Porters of her gates, or by ſome other perſon allowed to ſcrue within the Court, giuen knowledge of his name &amp; Countrey from whence he commeth, to be ſignified to the Lord Chamberlaine or Vicechamberlaine, or to ſome other perſon of her Maieſties priuie Counſaile, And thereupon, as the caſe ſhall require, to be licenced by any of them to come within the gates of her Court, and not to tarie any longer then they ſhalbe ſo licenced. And if the parties ſhal haue onely letters to deliuer to any with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in the Court, Then, not to come within the Court gates, but to ſend the ſame letters to the perſons to whom they are directed: from whom when they ſhal haue anſwere, they ſhal not longer continue neere to the Court, vpon paine of impriſonment. Finally, her Maieſtie commandeth that no maner of perſon allowed to attend in her Court, ſhal repaire to London, or to the ſuburbes or places within two miles of the Citie, without ſpecial li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cence of the Counſailor or other Officer vnder whom he ſerueth, in writing, to be ſhewed to any officer that ſhal ſeeke to impeach him, vpon paine to be impriſoned by attachment of the knight Marſhal, or of his officers, if the partie ſhall not ſhew in writing ſufficient warrant both for his going &amp; returning. Her Maieſtie alſo ſtraightly chargeth and commandeth the knight Marſhal of her houſhold, that he ſhall cauſe due ſearch to be made of all vagabonds, commonly called Rogues, that ſhal haunt about the Court, or in any places within the Verge, and them to apprehend and commit either to the Marſhalſea, or to deliuer them to the nert Conſtables to be ſent to the common gaoles next to the place where they ſhalbe apprehended, there to be ordered and puniſhed according to the lawes prouided for ſuch offenders.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>Giuen at her Maieſties Honor of Hampton court, <date>the twelfth day or October, <hi>1592,</hi> in the foure and thirtieth yeere of her Maieſties raigne.</date>
               </dateline>
               <lb/>
God ſaue the Queene.</closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <g ref="char:leaf">❧</g> Imprinted at London by the Deputies of CHRISTOPHER BARKER, Printer to the Queenes moſt excellent Maieſtie. 1592.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
